<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://sudeepacharya.com.np/categories/Random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Sudeep&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sudeepacharya.com.np/categories/Random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PTE vocabulary with meaning in Nepali - Most Common</title>
      <link>https://sudeepacharya.com.np/blog/2024/08/14/pte-vocabulary-meaning-nepali/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sudeepacharya.com.np/blog/2024/08/14/pte-vocabulary-meaning-nepali/</guid>
      <description>In this post, i will share most commonly repeated words and their meaning in Nepali as well as in English. Knowing the meaning of these words will help you a lot in scoring good marks in PTE.&#xA;Word Meaning in Nepali Meaning in English abjure प्रतिषेध, परम्परा to withdraw one&amp;rsquo;s word or professed belief Abruptly अचानक in a sudden, unexpected, and sometimes unpleasant way abstract सार a summary of the contents of a book, article, or speech abundant प्रचुर मात्रामा present in great quantity accretion वृद्धि growth or increase by the gradual accumulation of additional layers or matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to find the game art for your Game Project</title>
      <link>https://sudeepacharya.com.np/blog/2017/05/21/how-to-find-the-game-art-for-your-game-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sudeepacharya.com.np/blog/2017/05/21/how-to-find-the-game-art-for-your-game-project/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on a game development, i do programming and in the game if i require graphics then i hire designer. I was curious about how other indie developers like me manage the game assets. I asked in a Facebook group about this topic. Hopefully i got reply from Dozens of people. In this post i will share how they manage the game assets being a Game Programmer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
